M Raihan Rafiiful Allaam

Mid-Level UI/UX Designer

alamehan.github.io 🗹 raihanralam@gmail.com 📞 0857-7971-8640 🧿 Cibadak, Sukabumi

More than 2 years of experience in UI/UX design. Starting from research, designing user interfaces, to prototyping. Have worked on more than 10 design projects so far. Designing responsive websites, mobile apps, landing pages, building design systems, to designing logos and illustrations.

Professional Experience

PT KREASI KODE DIGITAL (CODIFY) - Malang

Dec 2021 - Apr 2023

A subsidiary of PT SOLUSI SINERGI DIGITAL TBK (SURGE)

UI/UX Designer - Full Time Remote

- Designing the LiniStore website user interface, fully-responsive. A social-commerce website with group buying feature. From research, interface design, to prototyping. 200+ pages in total.
- Designing the LiniSeller website user interface. LiniStore is for buyers, while LiniSeller is for sellers. Sellers can open an online store and sell their products on LiniStore. 100+ pages in total.
- Designing the **Kelola Gudang** mobile app user interface. An e-commerce fulfillment service that helps online sellers to focus on selling, operational management matters such as packaging to shipping products from the warehouse to the client are handled by Kelola Gudang's staff. 120+ pages in total.
- Designing the Kelola Gudang Staff mobile app user interface. Kelola Gudang is for online sellers, while Kelola Gudang Staff is for staff who helps with the operational management of the online sellers as instructed in the app. 70+ pages in total.
- Designing the Kelola Paket mobile app user interface. A package delivery app with a wide selection of the best expedition services. From research, interface design, to prototyping. 50+ pages in total.
- Designing the **Kelola Iklan** website user interface. A bidding website for advertising space. Connects media owners (ad space owners) and clients (ad space renters). From research, interface design, to prototyping. 70+ pages in total.
- Designing the **Kelola Bayar** widget user interface. A payment gateway service that handles balance top-ups and payments in the Kelola Super App environment.
- Designing both Kelola Super App and Kelola Gudang landing pages. A web page that contains information about the product and serve as a promotional tool.
- Designing report module interface for the **Kelola Gudang Portal** website. Kelola Gudang Portal is website view of Kelola Gudang mobile app. **Improving** website user interface, from the header, sidebar, table, color, spacing, iconography, and illustration.
- Build, manage, and maintain both LiniStore and Kelola Super App design system. From color system, typography, style, effect, spacing, grid, iconography, illustration, and basic components.
- Rebranding the Kelola Super App logo. Designing logos for Kelola Gudang, Kelola Paket, Kelola Asuransi, Kelola Bayar, Kelola TMS, Kelola ERP, and Kelola SAAS. Creating digital assets such as banner designs and illustrations. Create a brand guidelines for each rebranding process, and create a **guidebook** for LiniStore and Kelola Gudang.

AISC 2023 UNIVERSITAS PERTAMINA

Mar 2023 - Present

- Designing the AISC 2023 (AIChE Indonesia Student Conference) website user interface, fully-responsive. A website that displays information on annual events and competitions.
- Building and maintaining a responsive AISC 2023 website using **React UI library: Ant Design**.

ICHEC 2023 INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG

Aug 2022 - Mar 2023

- Designing the ICHEC 2023 (Indonesia Chemical Engineering Challenge) website user interface, fully-responsive. A website that displays information on annual events and competitions.
- Building and maintaining a responsive ICHEC 2023 website using React UI library: Ant Design.

ICHEC 2022 INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022

- Designing the **ICHEC 2022** (Indonesia Chemical Engineering Challenge) website user interface, fully-responsive. A website that displays information on annual events and competitions.
- Building and maintaining a responsive ICHEC 2022 website using React UI library: Ant Design.

Education

TELKOM UNIVERSITY - Bandung

2016 - 2021

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering - GPA: 3.61

- Internship at PT KONG TEKNOLOGI ASIA Bandung as UI Designer and UI Engineer.
- Final Project: Orchid Plant Genus Classification Using Deep Learning ConvNets.

SMA NEGERI 1 CIBADAK - Sukabumi

2013 - 2016

Natural Sciences Major

- Served as student council president for the 2014-2015 period.
- Served as the head of the IT Club extracurricular in 2014.

Certification

HABISKERJA.COM Mar 2023

UI UX Mastery Class: Website & Mobile Apps with Figma.

COURSERA.ORG Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

Google UX Design Professional Certificate.

SKILLACEDEMY.COM Mar 2020

UX Designer: Digital Product Development.

Skills

Design: User research, User flow, Wireframes, UI Design, Design system, Prototyping, Logo design, Illustration **Tools:** Figma, FigJam, Adobe XD, Balsamiq Wireframes, Fisamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Notion, Whimsical, Draw.io **Code:** HTML, CSS, Basic JavaScript, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, Basic React, Ant Design, Vite, Git, Visual Studio Code